all right
[Music]
my best seller how not to diet my
chapter on fat blocking food starts out
with a command to eat your thylakoids
doctor's orders
what the heck is a thylakoid just the
source of nearly all-known life and the
oxygen we breathe thyroids are where
photosynthesis takes place the process
by which the plants turn light into food
thylakoids are the great Green Engine of
Life microscopics act like structures
composed of chlorophyll-rich membranes
concentrated in the leaves of plants
when we eat thylakoids when we bite into
a leaf of spinach for example those
green leaf membranes don't immediately
get digested they can last for hours in
our intestines and that's when they work
their magic thylakoid membranes bind to
lipase lipase is the enzyme our body
uses to digest fat so if you bind the
enzyme you can slow fat absorption it's
like a natural version of the fat
blocking drug orlistat but without the
anal leakage this is because the effects
of the thylakoids are temporary unlike
the drug the thylakoids do finally break
down eventually freeing the lipase
enzyme to do its job before fat comes
spilling out your other end
ultimately fat absorption is not so much
blocked by thylakoids acid is delayed
if all the fat is eventually absorbed
what's the benefit
location location location
there's a phenomenon known as the ileal
break the ilium is the last part of the
small intestine before it empties into
your colon when undigested calories are
detected that far down in our intestines
our body thinks we must be full from
stem to stern and puts the brakes on
eating more by dialing down our appetite
this can be shown experimentally if you
insert a nine foot tube down people's
throats and drip in any calories fat
protein or sugar you can activate the
ileal break then sit them down to an
all-you-can-eat meal and compared to the
placebo group which just got a squirt of
water down the tube they eat over 100
calories less you just don't feel as
hungry you feel just as full eating
significantly less that's the ileal
break in action
so with thylakoids delaying calorie
absorption until that tail end of your
small intestine small satiety signals
are sent to the brain which dials down
your appetite if you feed someone a meal
with added thylakoid by slipping in some
powdered spinach and measure the level
of hormone releasing their bloodstream
over the next six hours you can see
significant rise in a satiety hormone
called cck and a drop in the Hunger
hormone ghrelin does this then translate
into a drop in appetite researchers were
eager to find out
spinach extracts were disguised in Jam
or juice to sneak thylakoids into meals
and those unwittingly eating the
equivalent of about a half a cup of
cooked spinach felt significantly less
hungry and more satiated over the next
few hours
give someone the equivalent of a shot of
wheatgrass juice in the morning or what
they might get in a green drink or green
smoothie and not only do they feel less
hungry more satiated their cravings for
presented salty sweet and fatty snacks
for example potato chips gummy bears
chocolate and cinnamon buns drop by
about a third feed them candy anyway and
those who unknowingly have been snuck
some spinach report liking the sweets
significantly less the c-shading power
of greens has been attributed to their
high water and fiber content and low
calorie density but the thylakoids may
be their secret weapon
most thylakoid trials have shown
improved satiety but the real test is
weight loss researchers in Sweden
randomized overweight women to Blended
blueberry drinks every morning with or
without green plant membranes in other
words just covertly slip some powdered
spinach and they get a boost in appetite
suppressing hormones
a decreased urge for sweets yes indeed
spinach can cut your urge for chocolate
check this out seven hours after eating
spinach you like chocolate yeah got any
more spinach
and
boom accelerated weight loss all thanks
to eating green the actual green itself
the chlorophyll packed membranes the
leaves
within 12 weeks the women who were slip
spinach lost 11 pounds significantly
more than the control group and as a
bonus their LDL cholesterol dropped too
even before the weight loss started
kicking in if you instead fix their
calorie intake to force the same weight
loss those randomized to the spinach
group may have had an easier time with
eating less experiencing less hunger
after a test meal after weeks eating
green
extracts of spinach were used in these
studies so they could create convincing
placebos but you can get just as many
thylakoids eating about a half cup of
cooked greens which is what I recommend
people eat at least two times a day and
my daily dozen checklist of all the
healthiest of healthy things I encourage
people to try to fit into their daily
routine
which greens have the most you can tell
just by looking at them because
thylakoids are where the chlorophyll is
The Greener the leaves the more potent
the effect so go for the darkest green
greens you can find which in my area is
the Lacinato or Dinosaur Kale
what happens when you cook greens
blanched for 15 seconds or so and steamy
or boiling water they actually get
brighter grain but then if you cook them
too long right they eventually turn kind
of a dry ball of brown when you overcook
greens the thylakoids physically degrade
along with their ability to inhibit
lipase but within that first minute or
so when the grain gets even more vibrant
there's a slight boost in fat blocking
ability so you can gauge the thylakoid
activity in both the grocery store and
the kitchen with your own two eyes
the best green vegetable though and the
best way to cook it is whichever and
however you'll end up eating the most
we've been chewing on leaves for
millions of years but today the greenest
thing about some people's diets may be a
Saint Patty's Day pint
Americans have averaged less than two
grams of spinach a day less than half a
teaspoon your body was designed to have
thylakoids passing through your system
on a daily basis so the delay in fat
absorption can be thought of as the
default normal State it's only when we
eat greens deficient diets that the
accelerated fat digestion undercuts are
natural satiety mechanisms
and the journal the Society of chemical
industry a group of food technologists
argued that given their fat blocking
benefits thylakoid membranes could be
incorporated into functional foods as a
new promising appetite reducing
ingredient
or you can just get them the way Mother
Nature intended
[Music]
foreign